Laura Aydelotte

Phone: (714) 658-3827 | Email: laurathecoder@gmail.com | Huntington Beach, CA LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/laura-aydelotte | Github: https://github.com/LauraAy | Portfolio: http://lauraaydelotte.com

Summary

Full-Stack Web Developer with project management and data management experience. Background as an educator and historian with excellent learning and communication skills. Collaborative colleague with creative approaches to digital planning and problem solving.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, Python, SQL, HTML, JSX, CSS, SCSS, SASS Applications: Wordpress, MongoDB, MySQL, MS Office, Excel, Photoshop, Access Database Data Formats: MARC 21, Dublin Core, DCRM, EAD, TEI, RDF, RDA

Selected Projects

Your World Cookbook | App: http://yourworldcookbook.com | Github: https://github.com/LauraAy/Your-World-Cookbook/

- A fullstack JavaScript application for entering recipes and attaching information about the region the recipe is from and more. React frontend and a backend built with a MySQL database using node.js, express, and sequelize
- My contributions: planned and developed the full stack application, designed and created photos and graphics for the UI
- Tools/languages Used: JavaScript, React, SQL, Sequelize, Node.js, Express, Material UI

Provenance Online Project | App: https://pop.library.upenn.edu/ | Github: https://github.com/upenn-libraries/subpop | Blog: https://github.com/upenn-libraries/subpop | Blog: https://pop.library.upenn.edu/ | Blog: https://pop.library.upenn.edu/ | Blog: https://pop.library.upenn.edu/ | Blog: https://pop.library.upenn.edu/ | Blog: https://provenanceonlineproject.wordpress.com |

- Description: Based at Penn Libraries, the Provenance Online Project (POP) is a book history project that allows historians to trace past owners of books from the middle ages to the present.
- My contributions: Project manager, leading a team from across departments. Worked closely with senior developers for the project and co-designed the data model. Made contributions to the project's front-end code, and code to provide search capabilities for the application.
- Tools/Languages Used: Ruby on Rails, SQL, Solr Blacklight, Bootstrap, Sass

Philadelphia Playbills Project | Github: https://github.com/upenn-libraries/playbills | Blog: https://philadelphiaplaybills.wordpress.com/

- The Philadelphia Playbills Project is an NEH funded project based at Penn Libraries that produced transcriptions of historic19th century Philadelphia Playbills, and converted those transcriptions into Linked Open Data (JSON-LD), available on the project's github.
- My contributions: Project lead (PI), managing every aspect of the project's work. Developed the schema for the data and contributed hands on work to data production and clean-up, including converting the JSON data to JSON-LD.
- Tools/languages used: Ruby, excel, oxygen, JSON, JSON-LD

Relevant Experience

Project Manager and Rare Books Curator University of Pennsylvania Libraries

2014-2019

Philadelphia,PA

- Directed two major digital humanities projects and multiple book digitization projects.
- Made substantial contributions to hands on coding, data modeling, and data management for projects.
- Led teams from across departments and acted as liaison between higher level administration and the data and development side.
- Directly supervised multiple assistants and part-time workers, and oversaw the work of developers, cataloging, and digitization staff.
- Wrote successful grants, worked with donors, and managed long term budgets.
- Created and maintained partnerships with over a dozen institutions outside my organization.
- Routinely delivered presentations and lectures internally and for the general public.

Digital Project Coordinator (full time consultant) Princeton University Library

July-Dec 2017

Princeton, NJ

• Produced a proposal for a Linked Open Data project based on a Princeton donor's collection of 18th century American books, and led collaboration with faculty, IT, developers, and librarians.

Additional Experience

Interim Assistant Director Center for Renaissance Studies Newberry Library

2011-2012

Chicago, IL

- Co-managed a consortium of 48 Research Universities and a budget of \$250,000
- Supervised a full time program assistant and three interns
- Organized and co-directed over 30 conferences, lectures, seminars, semester long courses, workshops, symposia, and institutes across the summer and academic year

University Lecturer University of Chicago

2007-2013

Chicago, IL

• Taught college level courses to undergraduates to first year graduates, including written composition, surveys of literature from the middle ages to the present, and advanced courses on Early Modern literature and culture including Shakespeare.

Education

- Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp, University of California, Irvine
- MLIS University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign
- PhD, Medieval and Renaissance Literature, University of Chicago
- M.A. English Literature, University of Chicago
- B.A. University of California, Santa Barbara